sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni jibun rashisa wo chikara ni
turn your sadness into kindness, your uniqueness into strength
mayoinagarademo ii arukidashite
even if you get lost, let's start walking
mou ikkai
one more time
dareka no kitai ni zutto kotae
are you really happy
homerarerunoga suki nano desuka
when you're always meeting to someone's expectations?
naritai jibun wo surikaetemo
even if you change to who you really wanna be
egao wa itsudemo suteki desuka
will you always have a great smile?
hajimaridake yume mite okiru
dreaming of only the beginning, I wake up
sono saki nara itsuka jibun no ude de
and someday, I'll live on my own.
souda daiji na mono wa itsumo katachi no nai mono dake
yes, precious things are never in shape
te ni iretemo nakushitemo kizukanumama
you never know what it is when you get it or lose it
sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni jibun rashisa wo chikara ni
turn your sadness into kindness, your uniqueness into strength
mayoinagarademo ii arukidashite
even if you get lost, let's start walking
mou ikkai
one more time
Release the Genjutsu and
wake up Naruto and Shikamaru.
He'll be getting a mission
after such a long while.
What do you mean by a mission?
Be careful...
It's the first A-Ranked mission
since the Land of the Waves.
Ouch!
You were able to release
the Genjutsu too!
Why were you pretending
to be asleep?!
Track down Sasuke,
join up and then stop him!
Then await next orders
in a safe place.
Huh? Did something happen to Sasuke?!
I'll tell you the reason en route!
Let's go!
H-Hey!
I get it! So that's what happened!
That Sasuke, getting all impatient!
So, why am I pulled into this?
This is such a drag!
It can't be helped!
It's Kakashi-sensei's order.
This way!
How long will it be until
we catch up?
I don't know.
He is moving at a pretty good speed.
Damn it!
Coward
N 1
o
It's Troublesome,
But I've Got to Do It!!
Hey! Hurry it up, you guys.
Huh? What is it?
Did you find Sasuke?
No!
There are eight people in
two squads behind us...
No...
There's one more...
There are nine people following us.
What?!
C'mon. Already?!
Give me a break!
It looks they haven't grasped
our location, yet.
We must lose them.
Hey, what's the point of stopping?!
Shut up and follow me!
Huh?
We're going back over our footprints.
If we do that,
it'll look to them like our footprints
suddenly disappeared.
But, they'll notice even
if we do this, right?
It'll buy us some time.
That's enough.
It'll be a matter for great celebration
if our pursuers get impatient,
cloud their eyes of pursuit
and lose sight of the trail.
Hurry!
There's no time.
I-I know!
This is not good.
Though they're on
alert for ambushes,
they're catching up with us
slowly, but surely.
Damn it!
Probably they're all Chunin or higher.
We'll be wiped out if they catch up.
Wiped out...
Damn it! Since it's come to this,
why don't we ambush them?!
Ambush?
Right.
Indeed, an ambush would
be to our advantage.
Even if the opponent has twice
the people than we do,
if we just catch them off-guard...
That's no good.
Our opponents are former
Leaf Shinobi Orochimaru's henchmen.
In the worst case scenario,
there might be Jonin.
I thought it'd work,
but I guess not, huh.
Hold it. Why?
The level of opponent doesn't have
much to do with an ambush.
What do you mean?
You guys don't get it.
Listen. Indeed, an ambush is
a very advantageous fundamental tactic.
But two conditions are necessary.
What are those necessary conditions?
Number one.
The ones on the run must act without
making noise and find the enemy first.
Number two.
One must be able to catch
the pursuers off guard,
capture a point and position
to be able to inflict certain damage,
and conceal oneself quickly.
Ah... Huh?
An ambush only becomes effective
when these two conditions are ensured.
Well, the first condition
won't be so difficult
since we have the Ninja Hound's nose.
And the second one also
seems advantageous at a glance
since we know the geography
of our village.
But Orochimaru has spent time
in the Leaf before.
That approach won't work
on his henchmen.
So what do you really mean?
Our pursuers must have been instructed
in the terrain of this village
and have gone through
simulated practice for this fight.
And on top of that,
they're probably all Ninja
who have mastered the pursuit arts.
So they know what cards we have, huh.
Well, even so, the fact remains
that an ambush is advantageous.
But there are too many elements
of uncertainty.
In the first place, the enemy is
a special unit organized for this operation.
But we have a fool...
a Kunoichi who's nothing special...
and one dog...
and, me with the number-one cold feet!
A tactic is grasping the conditions
that are there without fail
and formulating an optimal plan.
And so, there's only one thing
that we can do now...
One?
A diversion in the guise
of an ambush.
One person will remain,
pretend to ambush,
and delay the pursuers.
In other words...
bait.
Right. If we delay them,
they won't be able to grasp
the positions of the remaining three.
If we do that, we'll be able
to shake off our pursuers,
but the one who has become
the bait will probably...
die.
So, who's going to do it?
We need the dog to follow Sasuke.
That means...
Fine...
— I'll...
— I guess it has to be me.
Shikamaru?!
W-Why you?!
It's better than being wiped out, right?
Besides, among us,
the only one who is equal
to playing the bait
and who has the possibility
of surviving...
is me.
Shadow Possession Jutsu is an Art
originally intended as a delay tactic, so...
Well, I'll catch up later!
Now get going!
We're counting on you, Shikamaru!
Sakura-chan!
Yeah.
Was Shikamaru ever this reliable
of a character?
Be careful...
Shikamaru.
No matter how much you try to erase
the signs of your presence...
you're in plain view.
Hey! The enemy is approaching fast.
What did you say?!
I wonder if he's really
delaying the enemy.
Me with the number-one cold feet!
Don't tell me, Shikamaru...
Shikamaru will be okay!
Don't tell me, he ran away.
I said he'll be okay!
What'll be okay?!
He has a dirty mouth and
always says stuff is a pain.
But he wouldn't betray us!
He hardly ever says
he'll do something himself,
but he makes sure to do it
if he says it!
That's absolute.
I want to believe...
I want to believe, but...
Pick up the pace!
I somehow managed to
get away completely.
Their strides are irregular.
Urgency is probably increasing
their fatigue.
Sorry about that.
I was supposed to be the guy
with the number one cold feet.
It seems my character has
changed just a bit this time.
The fact that I'm tired is true.
Those footprints are wrong.
By the way, this is what
the dog's paw print really is.
Oh, he's still a kid.
To think we'd all get caught like this.
So this is the rumored Leaf Village's
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu, huh?
That's an old way of saying it!
The times are passing!
It's called Shadow Possession Jutsu now,
old man.
Sure enough,
that match wasn't good.
I used too much Chakra.
I can't hang on much longer...
1, 2, 3, 4...
5, 6, 7... 8.
Eight people...
Eight... No, there's one more...
There are nine people following us.
Sure enough, the ninth person's role is
to protect against them getting ambushed.
That person stays at a fixed distance,
moves in the back and responds
to an enemy attack.
But... this will make clear where
that person's hiding!
There, huh?!
Damn it... The Shadow won't reach.
I don't have the stamina to
send it to Chakra.
It's futile. I see through your technique.
Is this as far as it goes?
It looks like you're at your limit...
This Shadow Possession Jutsu
is going to break very soon.
Prepare yourself!
I wanted to...
become a Ninja any which way,
save up money any which way,
get married any which way to
an ordinary woman
who's neither beautiful nor ugly
and have two kids any which way.
First will be a girl, and then a boy...
I would retire from being a Ninja
when my eldest daughter marries
and my son becomes a full-fledged man.
And then I take it easy
in my life of retirement
playing Shogi
and Go the whole day.
Then I die of old age before my wife.
Such a life would've been nice.
I was out of character,
I tried too hard this time.
I wanted it to end in an ordinary way.
What I did was a drag...
Hmm, the movements of
our pursuers have stopped.
Yes! The delaying was a success!
Shikamaru, eh?
I'm sorry I doubted you, even a little.
Okay!
Now... you wait, Sasuke.
And... Shikamaru...
Live, and catch up to us no matter what!
As you say, it seems I'm at my limit.
Hey, come on out.
While you're at it, cut off his head.
I finally caught up.
A-Asuma?! Why?
Well done, Shikamaru.
Sure enough, out of character.
For the time being, you retire here.
Hurry!
What a pest.
The pursuers have increased?
Two? No, three?
Kankuro! Pick up the pace!
Okay.
I won't let you get away.
Don't jump the gun, Sasuke.
Sasuke-kun.
Now then, shall we begin?
dare datte shippai wa surunda hazukashii koto janai
everyone makes mistakes it's nothing to be ashamed about
kono kizu o muda ni shinai de waratte arukereba ii
don't let this scar be for naught walk with a smile
sou shizuka na kuuki suikomi hiroki sora ni kao age tobikomi
yes, breathe in the air and lift your face to the sky and jump
toki ni ame ga futtara hito yasumi jaa yukusaki wa kaze fuku mama ni
if it rains, take a break go where the wind takes you
takusan no matotteru koukai kono kizu o muda ni shicha shounai
so many regrets don't let this scar be for naught
ude ni kunshou kizami ikoukai shougai
let's go carve the in our chest
sou kokkara ga SHOW TIME
yes, it's show time, life begins now.
dare datte shippai wa surunda hazukashii koto janai
everyone makes mistakes It's nothing to be ashamed about
kono kizu o muda ni shinai de waratte arukereba ii
don't let this scar be for naught walk with a smile
kanashimi mo kaze ni kaete tsuyoku susunde ikereba ii
transform sadness into the wind and continue to forge on
tsuyoku susunde ikereba ii
forge on strong
I don't know what's going on!
Why is Old Man Hokage
fighting with Orochimaru?
Why is Sasuke going after
that guy with shadows around his eyes?
I don't understand why we have
to go after him,
but that's what we have to do right now!
Wait up, Sasuke!
Next time:
"Absolutely Incomparable! A Hokage Level Battle."
What the hell's happening
to the village?!